Guide to the Records of the Institute of Federal Taxation 1963-1991 RG 32.8
New York University Archives
Records of the Institute of Federal Taxation
1963-1991
RG 32.8
New York University Archives
2.0 linear feet 2 linear feet
The records of the Institute of Federal Taxation in this collection span from its creation in 1965 to 1982, although most documents in this collection date from the 1970s. The institute still exists and remains a part of the School of Continuing and Professional Studies. The purpose of the institute is to acquaint those who deal frequently with taxes with the nature of the taxation process and to clarify complicated taxation processes.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading then chronologically within each subject/author heading.
The files are grouped into one series.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the papers of several annual meetings of the Institute. There are also three folders with records of the International Institute on Tax and Business Planning.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Institute of Federal Taxation is a program that originated in the School of Continuing Education (currently the School of Continuing and Professional Studies), although it is also associated with the School of Law and the Stern School of Business. The Institute began in 1941 with presentations and seminars that intended to clarify the complexity of tax law and procedure for professionals seeking to better understand the topic. The Institute publishes a bound volume of proceedings and lectures for each annual meeting, which can last from several days to several weeks. Attendees of the Institute's programs include attorneys, accountants, and others who regularly deal with matters of taxation.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection.
Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted.
This collection is in
off-site storage
.
Provenance
The records were transferred to the University Archives from the School of Continuing and Professional Studies in 2002.
New York University. Division of General Education.; New York University. Institute of Federal Taxation.; New York University. Institute on Federal Taxation.; New York University. School of Continuing Education.; Continuing education.; Economics.; Finance.; Lectures and lecturing.; Taxation.
  - International Institute on Tax and Business Planning: Mexico, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227136 4
  - International Institute on Tax and Business Planning: Puerto Rico, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 34th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 1, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 34th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 2, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 26th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 21st Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 22nd Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 24th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 25th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - International Institute on Tax and Business Planning: Foreign Investment in the U.S. and the European Community, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227150 5
  - 36th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 1, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 36th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 2, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 37th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 1, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 37th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 2, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 38th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 1, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 38th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 2, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 40th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 1, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 40th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 2, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 49th Annual Institute on Federal Taxation, Part 1, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)